Guide to the University Historical Material records, 1821-2012 RG0031
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Images and visual works, 1859-1990; RG0031 Series 1; 21 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 34, Flat box 37, Box 42, Box 86, Box 95, Box 205, Box 206, Box 265, Box 267, Box 268, Box 269, Box 270, Box 271, Box 87, Flat box 89, Flat box 90, Box 91, Box 92, Box
  - NEGATIVES, Box 207: See note for contents (Box SHARED Box 14, Box 207)
    1: Group - Students sitting on bench by building 2: Peter Caws, Rod French, Lois Schwoerer, Phyllis Palmer, Sera Morgan at exhibit for Marcus Cunliffe 3: Students Bob Burton, Russ Herrold, Stu Brown, Jim Gonzalez,Kim-Andrew Elliot 4: People outside Bldg D- Public Administration 5: Two men looking up at building 6: Students studying in library 7: President Trachtenberg and student 8: President Trachtenberg with Rod Fench and Kyle Farmbry 9: Students studying in Lisner Library 10: Sharon Rogers unveiling new Aladin computer catalog in Gelman Library 11: Columbian Women (?) in a meeting 12: Rod French with a man receiing a medal 13: Engineers Wheels Pep Rally - three girls in hula skirts 14: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally - parade on G Street 15: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 16: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 17: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 18: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 19: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 20: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally - parade on G Street 21: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 22: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally - information booths 23: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally 24: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally -Tompkins Hall 25: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally -Tompkins Hall 26: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally - cheerleaders and students outside Student Union 27: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally - parade on G Street 28: Engineer's Wheels Pep Rally, Wedding 29: Wedding reception 30: Wedding reception 31: Wedding reception 32: Wedding reception 33: Wedding reception 34: Wedding reception 35: Wedding Picture 36: Wedding reception 37: Wedding reception 38: Wedding reception 39: Wedding reception 40: Wedding reception 41: Wedding reception 42: Wedding reception 43: 20th & G Streets, N.W. - students around the street sign c. 1955 44: Wedding reception 45: Sigma Nu XMas 46: Sigma Nu XMas 47: WRGW on the air 48: Diety Party 49: Diety Party 50: Diety Party 51: Diety Party 52: Diety Party 53: Diety Party 54: Diety Party 55: Diety Party 56: Visit to Mt. Vernon, Afghan & Turk students 57: Medallion 58: Dancers 59: Pres. Carroll with two men 60: Two people in cap and gown 61: Portrait of man 62: Man in military uniform 63: Portrait of woman 64: Portrait of a man 65: Portrait of a man 66: Portrait of a man 67: Men in uniforms in front of 2013 G Street 68: Two men talking 69: Pres. Carroll with four men 70: Portrait of a man 71: Man and a woman talking 72: Two people looking at art work 73: People in cap and gowns outside building 74: Two people looking at art work in a museum 75: Law School building c. 1950 76: Faculty in front of Dept. of Business and Public Administration 77: Two people looking at layout for magazine 78: Three men and two women talking 79: Portrait of a man 80: Two men in cap and gown 81: Staff 82: Tea cup 83: Two people looking at layout for magazine 84: Woman holding music box 85: Portrait of man 86: Portrait of a woman 87: Three men standing in front of GW statue in Lisner Library 88: Portrait of a man 89: Portrait of a man 90: Faculty in caps and gowns 91: Artist rendering of addition to GW hospital 92: Portrait of a woman 93: Football coach 94: Football coach with hat 95: Pres. Carroll with two men 96: Student portraits 97: Camp Fry Washington 98: Sigma Chi 99: Individuals in Caps and Gowns 100: Pres. Carroll and other man 101: Pres. Carroll, John Park, and two other men in front of Dept. of Business and Public Administration building 102: Columbian Women scholarship fund drive sign 103: Figurines 104: Dr. Seller 105: Individual 106: 2 Men in caps and gowns 107: Two people looking at layout for magazine 108: Group of men, most in uniform 109: Group in caps and gowns 110: Faculty in caps and gowns in front of 2013 G Street 111: 2 Men 1 in cap and gown, 1 in uniform 112: American Education Week poster, 11/11/1962 113: Man and a woman talking 114: Man and woman talking 115: Dr. John Parks and two women leaving hospital room 116: 2 Men talking 117: Men 118: Student portraits 119: Four men and one woman talking 120: Elmer Louis Kayser outside 2023 G Street 121: Group (in hospital room?) 122: Portrait of man 123: Dorm room (female) 124: Group of women-- indoor picture 125: Portrait of woman 126: Portrait of man 127: Portrait of man 128: Man sitting in front of (not U.S.) flag 129: Student portraits 130: Portrait of a man 131: Robert S. Jordan 132: 4 Men standing around a picture 133: Capitol building c. 1840 134: F.J. Lundine 135: J. Cochran 136: Law Review article about Supreme Court 137: Man and woman 138: Mansion c. 1900 139: Portrait of a man 140: N. Poynter
  - NEGATIVES, Box 208: See note for contents (Box SHARED Box 14, Box 208)
    1: People dancing 2: Jefferson Memorial 3: People standing around person at piano 4: 2 men, 2 Women standing 5: Woman sitting, 2 Men standing 6: 6 men standing in front of GW bust and conference table 7: Pres. Carroll and three men 8: Men in military uniforms standing in front of 2013 G Street 9: 2 Women in caps and gowns 10: Male speaker at large panel 11: 2 Men shaking hands in front of building 12: 2 men at Sharaton-Carlton hotel 13: Library 14: Four women stadning by table in gym 15: 4 Women and 1 man in a gym, 2 w/ golf clubs 16: Two men and a woman 17: Person in costume between 2 people 18: Dorothy Betts Marvin at reception with Pres. Carroll 19: Dorothy Betts Marvin at reception with Pres. Carroll 20: Dorothy Betts Marvin at reception with Pres. Carroll 21: Women's group reception 22: Three women sitting in chair, large painting w/ row boaters behind them+D328 23: 3 women (same) in crowd in art gallery 24: Group of five men (fraternity?) 25: Fraternity award, 3 men 26: 4 Men standing in front of chairs and drapes 27: 5 Men standing in front of chairs and drapes 28: 3 Men standing in front of chairs and drapes 29: Two students, man and woman, sitting on lawn 30: Men and Women at dining tables 31: Group backstage at lisner auditorium 32: Women at reception 33: Man and women in ethnic costumes dancing 34: 4 men around a desk, bowling bag, trophies 35: 3 Women in ethnic costumes 36: Women at reception 37: 3 Women by bookshelves 38: 6 Men standing behind a table 39: Three men standing by seal of GWU 40: Pres. Carroll and group of women (Columbian Women?) 41: Pres. Carroll and two men talking 42: 2 Women being shown a fish in a market 43: 3 Women, seated 44: 2 Men on stage 1 seated 45: Woman holding pub. Federal Hearing Examiners 46: 3 Men holding publication Federal Hearing Examiners 47: 3 Men standing 48: Large group of men at banquet 49: Men and women getting on a chartered bus 50: 3 women sitting and talking 51: Two women talking to standing man on a stage 52: Old university bookstore 53: Man at a microphone talking to dinner group 54: Three men talking
  - NEGATIVES, Box 209: See note for contents (Box SHARED Box 14, Box 209)
    3: Alumni Dinner 4: Alumni Dinner 5: Alumni Dinner 6: Alumni Dinner 7: Alumni Dinner 8: Alumni Dinner 9: Alumni Dinner 10: Alumni Dinner 11: Alumni Dinner 12: Alumni Dinner 13: Alumni Dinner 14: Alumni Dinner 15: Alumni Dinner 16: Alumni Dinner 17: Alumni Dinner 18: Alumni Dinner 19: Alumni Dinner 20: Alumni Dinner 21: Alumni Dinner 22: Alumni Dinner 23: Alumni Dinner 24: Alumni Dinner 25: Alumni Dinner 26: Alumni Dinner 27: Alumni Dinner 28: Alumni Dinner 29: Alumni Dinner 29.2: Alumni Dinner 30: Alumni Dinner 31: Alumni Dinner 32: Alumni Dinner 33: Alumni Dinner 34: Alumni Dinner 35: Gelman Library- building 36: Gelman LIbrary - 10th anniversary 37: Gelman Library - entrance 38: Gelman Library - people with banner stadning outside 39: Gelman Library 40: Gelman Library 41: Gelman Library - man shelving books c. 1973 42: Gelman Library - moving books on cart c. 1973 43: Gelman Library - men in construction hats c. 1973 44: Gelman Library - shelves waiting for books c. 1973 45: Gelman Library - crane outside c. 1973 46: Gelman Library - circulation desk c. 1973 47: Campus scene 48: Gelman Library - people at computers 49: Pres. James Welling 50: Pres. Needham 51: Student sleeping at table 52: Individual --Craig Zilkerman 53: Jacqueline Kennedy c. 1961 54: Student outside dorm room door 55: Hal Bergam 56: Columbian College Charter Act of Feb. 2, 1821 57: Pres. William Staughton 58: Student being interviewed at 1993 NCAA basketball championship 59: Lillian Skufea, Golf champion 60: Gymnast on balance beam 61: Navy Logisitics research office with 1401 computer 62: J. William Fulbright, LLB 1934 63: Abram Lisner 64: Cherry Blossom Princess in National Gallery of Art building 65: Major Walter Reed 66: Mabel Nelson Thurston 67: John Foster Dulles 68: Student looking at posters 69: Warrren Burger at podium 70: Portrait of man, 19th century 71: Man 72: Man standing by building 73: Man standing by building 74: Old library reading room c. 1920 75: Woman by empty shelves 76: Gelman library - reference desk 77: Woman at computer terminal 78: Book shelves in medical library 79: Students sitting in classroom 80: Convocation in honor of H.M. Albert, King of Belgium 81: Students sitting under tree in University Yard 82: Campus scenes c. 1973 83: Homecoming "Rallying before the rally" 84: Campus scene c. 1961 85: Trial for Students for a Democratic Society after their occupation of Maury Hall 86: Students sorority races 87: Old library reading room, 1920 88: Resurrection City on the Mall 89: Red Lion Row fire 90: Sound proof room in Lisner Auditorium Radio Studio 91: Campus scenes 92: Campus scenes 93: Student Rally at Resurrection City 94: Flame thrower from Allegheny Project 95: Dean Elmer Louis Kayser's class of Civilization, lecturing in Lisner Auditorium 96: Students playing cards 97: Classroom lecture 98: Woman at table'"Buy War Stamps" 99: Columbian University building, 15th and H Street, NW 100: Commencement invitation, National University 101: Mary Ralston 102: Woman standing in front of GW statue in Lisner Library 103: Man sleeping in chair 104: Dwight Eisenhower at podium, receiving Honorary degree? 105: Student with feet on a desk 106: Student studting on the grass 107: Woman at mircrophone 108: Woman sitting in classroom desk 109: Woman studying in library 110: Man studying 111: Gate and Key Open House 112: Gate and Key Open House 113: Gate and Key Open House 114: Gate and Key Open House 115: Man in control room at Lisner Auditorium 116: Control room at Lisner Auditorium 117: Engineering 118: Engineering 119: Engineering 120: Men in office 121: Man in front of Student Union 122: Man in front of Student Union 123: Student Council 124: Student Council 125: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 126: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 127: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 128: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 129: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 130: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 131: Visit to Mr. Vernon Afghan & Turk students 132: Regiment on 23rd Street
  - NEGATIVES, Box 210: See note for contents (Box SHARED Box 14, Box 210)
    1: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll [all from 5/3/1961], President Kennedy walking in procession, 1961 2: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, Carroll with family 3: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 4: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 5: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 6: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 7: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 8: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 9: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 10: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 11: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform, Pres. Kennedy standing 12: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 13: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, view of University Yard 14: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, speaker's platform 15: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President Kennedy at podium 16: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President Kennedy shaking hands 17: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President Kennedy receiving honorary degree 18: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President Kennedy at podium 19: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 20: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 21: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, three men 22: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, people talking 23: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, Cloyd Heck Marvin with two men 24: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, people talking 25: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 26: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 27: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 28: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 29: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 30: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 31: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 32: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 33: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 34: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, dinner 35: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President Kennedy with Carroll and Marvin (cropped) 36: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, audience 37: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President walking on stage with Carroll 38: Moot Court 39: Children sitting around piano 40: Poster showing steel Mgt. and Union (Berryman cartoon?) 41: 2 Women talking 42: Pres. Carroll talking with four men 43: Gathering -- group watching a speaker 44: Gala anniversary--Class of 1911 45: Gala anniversary--Class of 1911 46: 3 Men seated 47: U.S. Army (Corps of Engineers) "booth" 48: Event at Lisner Auditorium 49: Women and a man standing and talking 50: 3 Men standing/talking incl. Jack Marbury 51: "Freedom 7" space capsule 52: 4 men/3 in cap and gown, 2 holding diplomas 52: Men on a stage talking 53: Group of men and women standing 54: People at a reception 55: People on a stage speaking 56: Man and woman dancing 57: 4 men sitting around a table 58: 4 men sitting around a table 59: Men seated on stage with speaker, flags 60: 3 men and a woman sitting around a table 61: Classroom scene (Moot Court?) 62: 2 Women in contumes on a stage 63: President Carroll talking to two staff members 64: Large group of standing men and women 65: Large Orchestra 65.1: 7 Men standing, One holding certificate about Internship 66: Members of the Class of 1890 67: Man receiving a diploma 68: Women standing in front of building 69: Columbian Women? With Pres. Carroll 70: 3 Women talking 71: Dr. Henneberger and an exhibit on geology 72: "Henneberger Bends" exhibit on geology 73: 3 Men and a women sitting/ talking at meeting table (student government?) 74: President Carrol talking with a woman and three men 75: Two men and one woman talking 76: GWU women at samovar, men standing 77: Inauguration of Pres. Carroll, President Kennedy standing on stage with Carroll 78: Women handing an award to another 79: 3 Men standing and talking 80: 1 Man and two women standing and talking 81: Pres. Carroll and man sitting under portrait of George Washington 82: Sound effects control room 83: 3 Men in caps and gowns 84: 4 Men standing 85: 5 People in front of Lisner 86: 4 women standing 87: Orchestra Practice 88: Women and 3 men in caps and gowns 89: Orchestra Practice 90: Orchestra Practice- Musicians and conductor 91: 2 Women and a man in front of Lisner 92: 2 Men and 2 women at a social function 93: People at social function 94: 4 Men looking at a Book 95: 4 Men standing 96: 3 Men talking in Montgomery room 97: Social Function 98: 3 Women at social function 99: Political Cartoon 100: 5 People Standing Outside 101: 2 Women and a man talking outside 102: Man Speaking before a group 103: Ceremony 104: 2 Women and a Man 105: Large reception in grand room 106: 4 Men and 2 Women at social function 107: Library periodical room, veteran students Wheeler, Ward, Pherson, Dumaine, Jones, Stewart 108: President Carroll talking to three students 109: Columbian Women 110: Columbian Women 111: Political cartoon drawing on Algeria 112: Men in caps and gowns 113: Gathering of one women and 5 men 114: Large orchestra 115: Banquet 116: Men and women standing outside the Hall of Engineering 117: Men in front of building 118: Columbian Women (?) at a tea 119: 1 Man and 2 Women standing 120: International students at graduation 121: 2 Women and 1 man in front of building 122: Pres. Carroll with two women 123: Man and women at podium, seated audience 124: Man and women at podium, seated audience 125: Man and two women standing and talking 126: Audience listening to lecture 127: President Carroll with small Christmas tree and man smoking a pipe
  - NEGATIVES, Box 211: See note for contents (Box SHARED Box 19, Box 211)
    1: Men meeting around table 2: Men meeting around table 3: Men standing and talking 4: Pres. Carroll shaking hands in receiving lines 5: Pres. Carroll shaking hands in receiving lines 6: Pres. Carroll shaking hands in receiving lines 7: Women's tea 8: Men shaking hands in receiving line 9: Men viewing architectual plan 10: Board of Trustees Meeting 11: Board of Trustees Meeting 12: 3 doctors standing 13: 4 Men standing talking 14: 4 People standing in front of Monroe Building 15: Large Gathering of People, Board of trustees 16: 2 Men and bust donation 17: 2 Military men holding diplomas 18: 5 people standing inside alumni house(?) 19: 2 Women talking 20: 2 women and 4 men standing before portrait 21: 2 Men standing in front of portrait 22: Male student receiving an award 23: Woman student receiving an award 24: Men inside physics building 25: Men and women at a dinner 26: gathering of men 27: 3 Men at meeting table 28: Women name Mrs.Cox 29: Men at banquet table, and standing around 30: 2 lines of people shaking hands 31: Dimock reception room 32: People at reception 33: Men at reception 34: Reception 35: People at reception 36: Men in front of old building 37: Man and woman in cap and gown in front of GW statue 38: Three men standing in front of small bust of GW 39: Pres. Carroll (?) and man in front of small bust of GW 40: 5 Costumed dancers 41: Men and women at a dinner 42: 3 men with football trophey 43: 3 men at auditorium 44: Pres. Carroll and three people by plaque for GW memorial association 45: group at social gathering 46: 3 people at library counter 47: long banquet tables 47: men and women standing around in room with 48: Board of Trustees (?) sitting around table 49: Pres. Carroll and four other men 50: Men and women at banquet table 51: Large banquet 52: Receiving line with Pres. Carroll (?) 53: Men eating at long tables with folding chairs 54: Men eating at long tables with folding chairs 55: Men eating at long tables with folding chairs 56: "Orginial Thirteen" women graduates 57: "Orginial Thirteen" women graduates 58: 3 Men standing 59: Men at Podium at Presidential Arms 60: Five men at table Mr.Ely, Munves, Hannah, Merrifield, Hennessey, Maher 61: Women Speaking at long table to men and women 62: Lisner Auditorium 63: 3 Women in ethnic costume and 1 man 64: 4 Men and 2 women talking on stairs at Monroe 65: International students (?) 66: International students 67: International students 68: Dean Potts, 1914 Law group 69: 5 Men standing in front of empty classroom 70: 5 Men standing in front of empty classroom 71: Speaker with lots of people seated on stage 72: Assembly of men on Lisner Auditorium stage 73: Group of people on steps of U.S. Capitol 74: Man receiving award 75: Men and women at social gathering 76: Group of five women 77: Pres. Carroll at party receiving line 78: men and women standing and chatting 79: men and women standing and chatting 80: Large group of men and women standing around 81: Men shaking hands 82: Friends of the library 83: Lisner Library 84: Man receiving award 85: Group outside Lisner hall 86: National Law Center, 7th annual Law Day award 87: Pres. Carroll and three people 88: Pres. Carroll and Pres. Marvin (?) with three other people 89: Pres. Carroll shaking hands in receiving line 90: Group 91: Man and two women 92: Two women looking at map 93: 3 women standing outside in front of building 94: Faculty in cerimonial garb 95: Group of military men outside Lisner Auditorium 96: Women at a reception 97: Woman and 3 men standing and talking 98: Academic procession 99: Two men in academic robes shaking hands 100: 3 Women, 2 in identical dresses (costume?) 101: 3 casually dressed women standing by a window 102: 2 men and three women standing in front of Capitol Building 103: Ground breaking of Gelman Library 104: Gelman Library - card catalogs/people 105: Gelman library - 10th anniversary, Estelle Gelman on left 106: Gelman Library from H and 22nd Street, NW 107: Gelman Library - Pres. Trachtenberg opening 4th floor study room 108: Gelman library - 10th anniversary, Connie McCarthy, Estelle Gelman, Pres. Elliott, and "George" 109: Man on stage speaking to group 110: Woman searching for books on computer in Gelman Library 111: Group posing outside of Hall of Engineering 112: Group posing outside of Hall of Engineering 113: Group posing outside of Hall of Engineering 114: Group posing outside of Hall of Engineering 115: Six men sitting around table 116: Men on stage holding large novelty check 117: Group possing outside building 118: Group possing outside building 119: 3 People in caps and gowns (faculty?) 120: Four men and one woman in cap at gown at commencement 121: Large group at dinner party 122: Man adusting ceremonial gown of another 123: 2 women in caps and gowns (faculty?) 124: Men and women in caps and gowns (faculty?) 125: 3 Men standing and talking 126: 4 Men in caps and gowns 127: 3 Men in caps and gowns 128: 2 Men in caps ansd gowns, one in uniform 129: 2 women and one man in cap and gown shaking hands 130: 4 Men Standing 131: Group of men and women 132: Five men talking 133: Man receiving award 134: 3 Men, 2 in Ceremonial gown 135: 2 men in cap and gown 136: Men and women at a gathering 137: 3 men in caps and gowns 138: Man with two students in cap and gown 139: 2 men standing in front of portrait of Oswald Colclough
  - NEGATIVES, Box 212: See note for contents (Box SHARED Box 14, Box 212)